Guide to the New York Transfer Company Records MSS.507
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York Transfer Company Records
1853-1931
Fales Library and Special Collections
New York Transfer Company
MSS.507
4 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons and 3 custom ledger boxes
The New York Transfer Company provided services for the transfer and transportation of baggage within New York. This collection contains company minutes ledgers, financial ledgers, and one stock ledger. The ledgers document company meeting minutes, reports, customer and vendor accounts, financial information, and stock information. The ledgers date from 1853 to 1931.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor. Minutes ledgers are listed first, followed by financial ledgers, and one stock ledger is listed at the end.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown.
Historical Note
The New York Transfer Company was based in New York City and provided services for the transfer and transportation of baggage within New York. Services included pickup and delivery of customers' baggage to and from hotels, train stations, and ports.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains ledgers created by the New York Transfer Company. Minutes ledgers contain board of managers meeting minutes, earnings and expenses statements, committee reports and appointments, and annual reports of the president, treasurer, and auditor. Financial ledgers contain account information for customers and vendors. The stock ledger records the purchase and sale of shares by shareholders. The ledgers date from 1853 to 1931.
Carriers -- United States.; Luggage.
- Minutes ledger, 1870-1873 (Box 1)
- Minutes ledger, 1871-1874 (Box 1)
- Minutes ledger, 1873-1874 (Box 1)
- Minutes ledger, 1876-1888 (Box 2)
- Minutes ledger, 1889-1895 (Box 2)
- Minutes ledger, 1896-1902 (Box 2)
- Minutes ledger, 1902-1907 (Box 2)
- Minutes ledger, 1908-1917 (Box 3)
- Minutes ledger, 1915-1931 (Box 3)
- Financial ledger, 1853-1867 (Box 3)
- Financial ledger, 1878-1896 (Box 4)
- Financial ledger, 1880-1921 (Box 6)
- Financial ledger, 1916-1921 (Box 5)
- Stock ledger, 1870-1918 (Box 1)